# erinç **inci**

software engineer



#### about

↑ Dodurga Mah. Odabaşı Cad. 3441. Sok. Güvengir Önder Sit. 13/3 No. 6 Türkkonut Çankaya Ankara Turkey

Dec. 30, 1986

Married

+90 533 655 5430

erincinci@gmail.com
erincinci.com
merincinci
erincinci
erincinci

languages english, fluent italian, beginner turkish, native

## **summary**

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience specializing in Java, Python and Node.JS backend. Professional, creative with proven analytical skills. Adept at researching and developing highly available and scaled applications. Managing open source continuous deployment project MagePanel in spare time.

# **experience**

2013 - today

#### **COMODO**, Ankara TR

Senior Software Engineer

Crawler (*Team Leader*) - Working with Java 8, Python and Node.JS backend modules, as well as Java GWT frontend modules for managing Comodo's web crawler system. Collecting and analyzing crawled web site contents and information using ElasticSearch, MySQL and DigitalOcean.

AdTrust Ad Network (Developer) - Working mainly on ad selection Java 8 REST Web Services and Node.JS backend modules. Gained hands on experience on scalability, various data stores (ElasticSearch, Cassandra, Hadoop, MySQL), caches (Redis, Memcache), message brokers & task queues (RabbitMQ, Kafka, Beanstalkd), frameworks (Spring, Jersey, Storm, Angular.JS) and cloud systems (AWS).

Following Scrum agile development methodology in a specialized scrum team using **Jira** and **Confluence** tools.

As part of the projects, using **GIT** as revision control system, **Jenkins** as continuous integration system and self-developed **MagePanel** as deployment automation system. Worked with **CentOS** and **Ubuntu** servers, installed technologies and maintained modules in production and staging environments.

2012 - 2013

## erbul, Ankara TR

Software Engineer

Developed Turkish Vaccine Tracking System's backend low-level message processing module with Java, using Netty & Storm frameworks and MongoDB datastore.

Developed web based **ASP.NET** business applications in **C#** for Turkish Ministry of Health using **DevExpress** framework.

Also managed company's transition process in revision management (GIT with GitBlit UI) and continuous integration systems (Jenkins).

2011 - 2012

#### ● KOVAN Research Lab., Ankara TR

R&D Enginee

Together with my colleague Fatih Gökçe, we successfully completed the research project funded by Turkish Aerospace Industries (TAI). ArduCopter open-source platform was used and modified with other components like additional Gumstix on-board computer, XBee radio modules and extra sensors. For demonstration, three quad-rotors were flown autonomously in a leader-follower layout. Arduino flight controller software was modified with C++, and coordination module software was developed with C. Worked with Ångström linux on Gumstix, managing sensor hardware drivers and coordination module.

2010 - 2010 Ossabest

#### Ossabest AASU, Savannah GA

Part-time Software Engineer

Project was funded by the National Science Foundation. Worked in a team developing a web-based user interface for manipulation of field sensor data. **JavaServer Pages** technology was used.

## papers

2016 A Privacy Preserving Anti-Malvertising System

1st author
International Symposium on Cyber Defence and Security

(ISCyDES'2016)

2015 Privacy Preserving Secure Online Advertising 3rd author

Istanbul University - World Conference on Technology, Innovation and

Entrepreneurship

## education

2012 - 2015 • Middle East Technical University (GPA 3.45) Ankara TR

M.Eng. in Computer Engineering

2009 - 2010 \*\*Armstrong Atlantic State University (GPA 4.0) Savannah GA

B.S. in Computer Science (Courses taken for a year - Not completed)

2004 - 2011 **© Gazi University** (GPA 2.64)

B.E. in Mechanical Engineering

2001 - 2004 **TED Ankara High School** Ankara TR

# projects

2015 - 2016 Where2Eat Android App Play Store: https://goo.gl/MTfkER

An android application for randomizing selection of nearby venues (restaurants, bars, etc.) according to multiple parameters. Used **Java** 

and Location API with Foursquare API for venues.

2014 - 2015 MagePanel - Deployment Automator erincinci.github.io/magepanel

Deployment automator UI, using Magallanes project in the backend. Written with **Node.JS express** framework and **Twitter Bootstrap** components. Also taking advantage of **Socket.IO** and **jQuery** 

frameworks.

2014 Behavioral Ad Targeting Prezi: https://goo.gl/e6CTa3

For fulfilling graduation project requirement in METU Computer Engineering Master's Degree, this project was designed to guess user intentions based on their past web usage, and target appropriate advertisement to them to increase the chance of getting a click. **Hadoop** is used for storing past web usage, **Mahout** library is used for data mining and a **Java** web service is used for selecting appropriate advertisements in real-time. This project is also accepted in COMODO AdTrust and is planned to be integrated into the product.

## certificates

August 2015 CS190.1x: Scalable Machine Learning

Honor Code Certificate (https://goo.gl/QSrejQ)

edX Berkeley

Ankara TR

## awards

Academic Excellence Award for the 2009-2010 Academic Year

# **voluntary** work

2005 - 2009 Ankara Anittepe Rotaract Club

Secretary duty between July 2008 and June 2009

Ankara TR